Hello, my name is Angus Willows, and I want to tell you a little bit about my experience
with the Amazon FBA, and give you a few golden nuggets of information that I've learned along
the way.
In college, I invented the kangaroo hanger, which is essentially a big paper clip
that clips in all of your clothes.
The kangaroo hanger was first produced in Asia, and I started
out selling it on Amazon about two years ago, using Amazon FBA.
Then, about a year and
a half ago, we transitioned to US manufacturing, and we're still using FBA because it just
makes the most sense financially for the business.
One of the main benefits of Amazon FBA, which
I'm sure you've heard of before, is the prime badge.
When I'm shopping online and
there's something that I need urgently, and it says it's going to be delivered in a week
or two weeks, I usually just skip over that and move on to something else.
And so that's
why it's so critical to have the prime badge on Amazon, and one of the best ways to get
that is through FBA.
The kangaroo hanger is made and shipped from Wisconsin, and so the
benefit of that is we can fulfill individual customer orders from our Wisconsin facility.
But we've actually found that using Amazon FBA is cheaper, so shipping the product to
Amazon, and then having them fulfill it to the end customer is actually cheaper for us
than shipping it directly to the end customer from our facility in Wisconsin.
And one of
the main reasons for that is because Amazon gets significant discounts on their shipping.
So the cost of shipping on Amazon is significantly lower than even wholesale rates from carriers
like UPS.
Here's my main tip when starting out with FBA.
You don't necessarily need to
go all in.
What we did with kangaroo hanger was we started out by shipping only our top
selling SKUs to Amazon FBA and having them fulfilled through Amazon.
And we kept our
slower selling SKUs as in-house Amazon fulfilled by merchant.
Thanks for watching, and if you
ever need hangers, keep an eye out for the kangaroo hanger.